Guide to the Betsy Beinecke Shirley Collection of American Children's Literature
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Authors and Illustrators for Children, 1719-2001; Series I; 8.38; (21 boxes)
  - Tolkien, J. R. R. (John Ronald Reuel)
    - Letter to Joy Hill, regarding serialization of The Hobbit, 1964 Aug 14 (Box 15, Folder 329)
  - Towne, Lucretia
    - Manuscript book, "A New Mother Goose being a collection of original rhymes & jingles"; holograph, illustrated by William Henry Furness, circa 1873 (Box 15, Folder 330)
      Created for sale at a fair benefitting the Pennsylvania Society for the Prevention of Cruelty to Animals
  - Travers, P. L. (Pamela Lyndon)
    - Letter to "Betty," regarding the Russells at Katonah, "Jessie," "the baby," and Vanessa Conrad; and a letter from Reynal and Hitchcock to Alice Steinlein, Greenwood Bookshop, Wilmington, Delaware, regarding Mary Poppins, 1934, 1940 (Box 15, Folder 331)
  - Tyler, Mary Elizabeth Sawyer
    See: Hale, Sarah Josepha Buell
  - Tyler, Moses Coit
    - Letter to A. H. Dooley, regarding his History of American Literature, 1878 Mar 20 (Box 15, Folder 332)
  - Van Loon, Hendrik Willem
    - Drawing, "Carthage"; watercolor on paper, with ink vignette below of Van Loon drawing "Carthage", 1921 (Box 15, Folder 333)
    - Drawings (8) for The Message of the Bells, or What Happened to Us on Christmas Eve; watercolor and ink on paper, 1942
    - Leaf from A Short History of Discovery, inscribed to Van Wyck Brooks, 1918 Jan 3 (Box 15, Folder 334)
  - Walle, Gustave
    - Portrait of Samuel L. Clemens; cut paper and ink silhouette on paper, 1909 (Box 15, Folder 335)
  - Walt Disney Productions
    - Drawing, "The Faithful Little Men Watched Over Their Princess," for Snow White and the Seven Dwarfs; pencil on paper, circa 1937
    - Drawing, "An Unhappy Happy," animation cell for Snow White and the Seven Dwarfs; paint on celluloid, framed, circa 1937
    - Illustrator's dummy for Walt Disney's Pinocchio, by Campbell Grant, 1947 (Box 15, Folder 336)
    - Story board sheets (2) for Ben and Me, after Robert Lawson; crayon on paper mounted on paper, 1953
  - Watts, Isaac
    - Letters (2) to Cotton Mather, regarding packets of books sent, 1719, 1727 (Box 15, Folder 337)
  - Webster, Jean
    - Manuscript of Daddy-Long-Legs; typescript carbon with illustrations, undated (Box 16, Folder 338)
  - Webster, Noah
    - Certificate assigning title to one share of the Union School House, New Haven, to Stephen Alling, then transferred to Andrew Kidston of Franklin Chapter No. 2, Royal Arch Masons, 1802 Jan 20 (Box 16, Folder 339)
    - Letter to Jedidiah Morse of Boston, regarding the origin of the federal government; accompanied by letter from Charles Bromback to Edna H. Greenwood, 1797 May 1, 1933 Jan 21 (Box 16, Folder 340)
    - Letter to Mssrs. Richardson, Lord, and Holbrook of Boston, regarding licences for his spelling books, 1831 Jun 9 (Box 16, Folder 341)
    - Letter to N. N. Henkle [?] of Indianapolis, regarding criticism of his Bible, his speller, and his dictionary, 1836 Jan 25 (Box 16, Folder 342)
  - Weiss, Harry B. (Harry Bischoff)
    - Letter to Mrs. A. E. Little, regarding Weiss's book on William Charles, 1933 Dec 18 (Box 16, Folder 343)
      Removed from Shirley +341
  - Wells, Carolyn
    - Letters (4) from Edith Kermit Roosevelt, regarding books and invitations to visit, 1903-1925 (Box 16, Folder 344)
      Removed from Shirley 4010
    - Manuscript of "The Intelligent Hen"; holograph, undated (Box 16, Folder 345)
  - Whittier, John Greenleaf
    - Manuscript of "Maud Muller"; holograph, bound and illustrated with five pencil drawings, undated (Box 16, Folder 346)
    - Letters (2) to "My Dear Friend" and "Dearest", 1872, 1879 (Box 16, Folder 347)
      Removed from Shirley 3382
  - Wiese, Kurt
    - Drawing of Eskimo girl; ink and watercolor on paper, undated (Box 16, Folder 348)
    - Drawings (20) for The Great All-Star Animal League Ball Game, by Vincent Starrett; ink and pencil on paper, with proof print of title page, circa 1957 (Box 16, Folder 349)
    - Drawings (2) for Ootah and His Puppy, by Marie Ahnighito Peary; ink and charcoal on card; with a letter from Wiese to the author, 1941, 1942 (Box 16, Folder 350)
  - Wilder, Laura Ingalls
    - Letter to Josephine Di Massa, regarding Farmer Boy, 1938 Dec 1 (Box 16, Folder 351)
  - Williams, Chester
    - Letter to Daniel Henchman of Boston, regarding Dr. Watts' Catechism for Children, 1753 May 7 (Box 16, Folder 352)
  - Winter, Milo
    - Drawing, "Beffa settled down comfortably," for Nuova, or The New Bee, by Vernon Kellogg; ink on paper, circa 1920
  - Young, Art
    - Drawings (2) for "Little Boy Blue," by Eugene Field; ink and pencil on paper, 1897 (Box 16, Folder 353)
    - Drawing for "Long Ago," by Eugene Field; ink on paper, 1897
    - Drawing for "Seein' Things," by Eugene Field; ink on paper, 1897
  - Young, Asaph M.
    - Manuscript book, "Historical Paintings" of Bible passages illustrated with watercolor drawings; holograph, 1826 (Box 16, Folder 354)
  - Zemach, Margot
    - Drawing for Jake and Honeybunch Go to Heaven; watercolor and pencil on illustration board, circa 1982
  - Multiple authors
    - Autographs of authors listed in Jacob Blanck's Peter Parley to Penrod (1938), 1876-1939, undated (Box 16, Folder 355)
      Signatures of Thomas Nelson Page, Gene Stratton-Porter, Booth Tarkington, Charles Asbury Stephens, William Allen White, and A. D. T. Whitney
    - Autographs of authors, miscellaneous, undated (Box 16, Folder 356)
      Signatures of Edward Ardizzione, Roger Duvoisin, Louise Fatio, Christopher Morley, and Sterling North
  - Unidentified artists and authors
    - Drawing, "A worky-day fortune;" ink and wash on paper, 1881 (Box 16, Folder 357)
    - Drawing of woman addressing letter in post office, signed "G."; ink on illustration board, undated (Box 16, Folder 358)
    - Drawing ["Amsterdam St. Nicholas"], signed "HGH"; watercolor and ink on illustration board, undated
    - Drawings (2) of "Dickens [sic] last reading," possibly by Hamilton; pencil on paper, undated (Box 16, Folder 359)
    - Drawing of Little Red Riding Hood and the wolf, signed "W"; ink on bristol board, circa 1880 (Box 16, Folder 360)
    - Drawing of two children playing with blocks, signed "W"; ink on bristol board, undated
    - Drawing for cover of "Saalfield's Annual"; ink and watercolor on bristol board, 1910 (Box 16, Folder 361)
    - Drawing for cover of Spencer's New Copy Books; ink, wash, and pencil on paperboard, 1884
    - Drawings (13) for "Mother Goose" tales; ink and pencil on paperboard, undated (Box 16, Folder 362)
    - Drawings (4) of anthropomorphic animals and human caricatures; ink and pencil on paper, undated (Box 16, Folder 363)
    - Harlequinade, metamorphosis (incomplete), initialed "I.D.," in four panels; watercolor and ink on paper, 1773 (Box 16, Folder 364)
    - Invoice for group children's books and toys bought by William F. Moody, circa 1865 (Box 16, Folder 365)
    - Manuscript book, "The American Toilet," after Stacey Grimaldi; holograph with illustrations, undated (Box 17, Folder 366)
    - Manuscript book, "The Christmas Gift"; holograph with illustrations, 1836 (Box 17, Folder 367)
    - Manuscript book, "The Toilet," after Stacey Grimaldi; holograph with illustrations; made in New Brunswick, New Jersey, 1828 (Box 17, Folder 368)
    - Manuscript book of verses and pictures; holograph illustrated with ink and watercolor drawings, bound in paper covers, 1790s (Box 17, Folder 369)
    - Manuscript magazine, "The Evening Star, published by the Ladies and Gents of the Rho Sigma Lyceum"; holograph, 1861 Nov 5 (Box 17, Folder 370)
    - Manuscript magazine, "The School Gem, Devoted to the Improvement of the Intellect and Heart"; holograph, 1858 Jan 9 (Box 17, Folder 371)
    - Manuscript magazine, "The School-boy's Magazine," Springdale, Iowa; holograph, 1858 (Box 17, Folder 372)
    - Manuscript magazine, "The Snow Flake," West Branch, Iowa; holograph, 1859 (Box 17, Folder 373)
    - Play script, "Norfolk Tragedy or The Children in the Wood"; holograph, 1817 (Box 17, Folder 374)
      Inscribed: "Played with puppets in the winter of 1817 in Philadelphia"; contains list of cast and stage directions; cover monogrammed: "David F. White"; also contains indexed list of books in the family library
    - Poem, "Our Lane, an English Verse," clipped from the Daily Picayune, New Orleans, 1867 Nov 9 (Box 17, Folder 375)
      Removed from Shirley 3355
  - Printing blocks and plates
    - Anderson, Alexander, design with woman seated near window operating breast pump; engraved boxwood block, undated (Box 18, Folder 376)
    - Barber, John Warner, designs (2) of two birds and a tree, and three men; engraved wood blocks, undated (Box 18, Folder 377)
    - Cady, Harrison, illustrations for The Adventures of Bob White and The Adventures of Sammy Jay, by Thornton Burgess; halftone plates (2), circa 1919 (Box 18, Folder 378)
    - Denslow, W. W. (William Wallace), bookplate for Edna Browning Wilkins; electrotype plate, circa 1901 (Box 18, Folder 379)
    - Garis, Howard, Uncle Wiggly Goes Camping; electrotype plates (2), circa 1940 (Box 19, Folder 380-381)
    - Hogrogian, Nonny, design of apples and cranberries; cut wood block, undated (Box 19, Folder 382)
    - McLoughlin Bros., Inc., "All About Santa Claus"; engraved wood block, undated (Box 19, Folder 383)
    - McLoughlin Bros., Inc., cover for "Aunt Oddamadodd series" of books; design by Thomas A. Cuzner; electrotype plate, circa 1865 (Box 19, Folder 384)
    - McLoughlin Bros., Inc., cover for "Gilt Cover Picture Book"; design by Edward Cogger; engraved wood blocks (21), circa 1870 (Box 20, Folder 385)
    - McLoughlin Bros., Inc., illustration of boy and girl examining book; design by Mumburger; engraved wood block, circa 1855 (Box 20, Folder 386)
    - Upham, Elizabeth, Little Brown Bear; electrotype plate, numbered 101, 1952 (Box 20, Folder 387)
    - Unidentified artists, designs (2) of a bird, and a woman in colonial dress; engraved wood blocks, undated (Box 20, Folder 388)
    - Unidentified artist, "The Capitol at Washington"; lithographic stone, undated (Box 21, Folder 389)
- American History and Educational Materials, 1640-1966; Series II; 4; (9 boxes)
  Series II is arranged alphabetically. Works by unidentified artists and authors are filed at the end.
  The series reflects Betsy Shirley's interest in the education of children, as well as her general interest in American history, as shown in documents, letters, photographs, and a variety of albums, as well as workbooks, samplers, and other examples of children's schoolwork. It holds one of the earliest statements known regarding education in the American colonies: the 1640 will of George Alcock written in the hand of noted teacher John Eliot (1604-1690), then serving as a scribe. Perhaps through Eliot's influence, or that of the Reverend Thomas Weld (1590?-1662), who also signed the will, Alcock specified that funds were to be set aside for the education of his children. Penmanship exercises and copybooks are well represented in the Shirley Collection, and exemplars abound. Perhaps the most notable are those kept by the young Hancock brothers, John (1737-1793) and Ebenezer (1741-1819) in the 1750s, which have pages lined with their practice alphabets and script, including those featuring John Hancock's iconic signature; the pages were together in one volume when acquired by Betsy Shirley in 1991 but were divided into two groups before they arrived at the library. Another small volume was filled by Allan Melvill (1782-1832) in 1793 while a student at the West Boston Academy, a writing school run by Oliver Wellington Lane (1751-1793). Melvill carefully copied full business letters, invoices, promissory notes, and announcements into his book in a variety of hands that mimic copperplate engraving. He grew up to become an importer of French and Italian fancy goods with shops in New York and Boston, as well as the father of author Herman Melville (1819-1891), who appears in Series I. The cover of the copybook features an etching of "The Macaroni Dray Man" (1791) published by Carington Bowles, which was likely hand colored by the young scholar.
  Among others, the five commonplace, penmanship, and autograph albums kept by Philadelphia Quaker schoolgirls and sisters Mary (1797-1827) and Rebecca Trotter (1791-1815) are good examples from the first quarter of the nineteenth century, as are the arithmetic workbooks kept by Henry and Mary Conklin and Joseph Rappleyea. Betsy Shirley also acquired a few embroidered samplers to show another category of school work created by students, both at home and at school. Schoolwork pieces from the twentieth century are fewer in quantity, but include a handmade construction paper booklet holding work by Roscoe Hersey (1910-1992, Yale BA 1933, BFA 1935), the son of a missionary and older brother of author John Hersey; it has examples of Roscoe's arts and crafts handiwork created at the Talbert School in Tientsin, China, in 1914-1917, including paper folding, sewing, weaving, and drawing. A later workbook made by student Susan Steinberg holds sewing samples, and two folders of excuse notes from the turn of the century show reasons why students didn't attend school at all.
  Advice given to children was another collecting area for Betsy Shirley, and here again are important examples of letters from John Adams to his grandson George, Benjamin Franklin to his grandson Benjamin, Francis Scott Key to his son Charles, and George Washington to his nephew George. Some pieces in the series were made simply for entertainment or pleasure, such as the clever album "Pictures from Life," which was "designed and executed" for Caroline Frothingham Neal by her cousin Ellen in Providence, Rhode Island, in 1865; it contains collages created using figures cut from fashion plates, with a narrative inscribed below in ink telling the story of siblings Fanny and Charley and their friends.
  The education of Native Americans is represented by a cache of prayers and catechism texts in the series, written out in the Assiniboine, Chelan, and Clallam languages, as well as a book of texts and illustrations prepared by students at the Toadlena Boarding School in Toadlena, New Mexico. Betsy Shirley's wider interest in religion is demonstrated by her acquisition of the diary of Mary Elizabeth Flint Whiting (1823-1891) of Hartford, Connecticut, the young wife of Rev. Samuel M. Whiting (1825-1878), who had been assigned to Sibsagar, Assam, India, with the American Baptist Missionary Union. Her two-part diary is a daily record of shipboard life, noting events, activities, and sicknesses, interspersed with her thoughts as a newly married wife of one of two young missionaries on the bark Washington Allston, which was returning a group of preachers, teachers, and natives to Assam from Boston. The Whitings served for ten years in India, after which they returned to New England and Elizabeth Whiting became secretary of the Women's Missionary Society in Connecticut.
  - Abbott Female Academy
    - Receipts (2) for tuition and board for Mary Taylor; printed forms, 1868 (Box 22, Folder 390)
  - Adams, Hannah
    - Letter to Elizabeth Peabody, regarding William Ellery Channing, 1823 Sep 11 (Box 22, Folder 391)
  - Adams, John
    - Letter to George Washington Adams, regarding school work; accompanied by engraved portrait of Adams, 1812, circa 1826 (Box 22, Folder 392)
  - Adams, John Quincy
    - Letter to Thomas Boylston Adams, regarding news from his voyage, 1779 Dec 12 (Box 22, Folder 393)
  - Barnes, Rebecca
    - Birth record; holograph, undated (Box 22, Folder 394)
  - Bartlett, Fanny
    - Diary, 1862 (Box 22, Folder 395)
  - Bartlett, Hannah
    - Hymnal, "Hannah Bartlett's Singing Book"; holograph, 1794 (Box 22, Folder 396)
  - Belcher, Polly
    - Workbook for penmanship, Canton, Connecticut; holograph, 1813-1815 (Box 22, Folder 397)
  - Burr, Aaron
    - Letter to Joseph Alston as introduction for Charles Wille, 1816 Jan 25 (Box 22, Folder 398)
  - Capen, Amity
    - Essay, "Education"; holograph, undated (Box 22, Folder 399)
  - Choate, Ruth B.
    - Autograph album, Naples, Maine; "Flowers of Loveliness" album published by J. C. Riker, New York, 1851-1882 (Box 22, Folder 400)
  - Cleveland, Grover
    - Letter to Edward G. Blaisdell, regarding commendation for rescuing a schoolmate from drowning, 1889 Feb 22 (Box 22, Folder 401)
  - Coburn, Betsy
    - Legal complaint against John Jackson for impregnation; holograph, 1822 (Box 22, Folder 402)
  - Conklin, Henry
    - Workbook, "The Double Rule of Three," for arithmetic; holograph, 1815 (Box 22, Folder 403)
  - Conklin, Mary
    - Workbook, "Addition of Federal Money," for arithmetic; holograph, circa 1815 (Box 22, Folder 404)
  - Covert, Anna Maria
    - Workbook, "Sketches and School Exercises," for drawing; watercolor, ink, and pencil, 1840 (Box 22, Folder 405)
  - Cunningham, Elbridge
    - Document, reward notice for return of Sarah Garland, 1843 Nov 1 (Box 22, Folder 406)
  - Eaton, Burnet
    - Contract to supply provisions for his father Barnabas Eaton, 1838 (Box 23, Folder 407)
  - Einstein, Albert
    - Letter to Robert G. Stillwell enclosing letter to his students, regarding their question "What is an animal?"; holograph, 1953 Jan 17 (Box 23, Folder 408)
  - Eliot, John
    - Will of George Alcock, specifying funds for the education of his children, 1640 (Box 23, Folder 409)
  - Emmons, Samuel
    - Receipt from Rufus Webb for schooling for Robert and Hannah Emmons, 1802 Oct 29 (Box 23, Folder 410)
  - English, Mary Hollingsworth
    - Indictment against English for bewitching Elizabeth Hobert of Salem, 1692 (Box 23, Folder 411)
  - Fleet, Thomas and John
    - Receipt issued to Joseph Tyler for Boston Evening-Post subscription, 1772 Dec (Box 23, Folder 412)
  - Franklin, Benjamin
    - Letter to Benjamin Franklin Bache, regarding his education, 1783 May 2 (Box 23, Folder 413)
  - Fritchie, Barbara
    - Documents (2) regarding legal agreements with Christian Steiner; holograph, 1858, 1861 (Box 23, Folder 414)
  - Gammon, Elizabeth
    - Sampler, embroidery on linen, circa 1795
  - Gaylord, Roxana
    - Remembrance album, Ashford, Massachusetts; holograph, 1833-1842 (Box 23, Folder 415)
  - Grant, Ulysses S. (Ulysses Simpson)
    - Letter to Roland Worthington, regarding his butler's son, Robert Heberton Terrell, Harvard Class of 1884; accompanied by a carte-de-visite photograph of Grant and his family, 1882, undated (Box 23, Folder 416)
  - Graffam, Mary
    - Sampler; embroidery on linen, 1794
  - Griva, Edward
    - "Prayers and Catechism in the Moses language"; typescript carbon, circa 1910 (Box 23, Folder 417)
    - "Prayers in the Moses language"; typescript carbon, corrected, circa 1910 (Box 23, Folder 418)
    - "Prayers in the Chelan Indian language"; manuscript carbon, circa 1910 (Box 23, Folder 419)
    - "Prayers in the Columbia Indian language"; typescript carbon, corrected, circa 1910 (Box 23, Folder 420)
    - "Small Catechism - Complete Catechism - Prayers in the Assiniboin Language"; typescript carbon, corrected, circa 1910 (Box 23, Folder 421)
  - Gwynne Temporary Home for Children
    - Receipt for turkey and plum pudding, 1892 Nov (Box 23, Folder 422)
  - Hancock, Ebenezer
    - Workbook for penmanship; holograph, 1757-1758 (Box 23, Folder 423)
  - Hancock, John
    - Workbook for penmanship; holograph, 1753 (Box 23, Folder 424)
  - Harrington, Mary S.
    - Diaries (2), 1880, 1883 (Box 23, Folder 425)
  - Hersey, Roscoe
    - Scrapbook, "Work Done in the Talbert School, Tientsin, China", 1914-1917 (Box 23, Folder 426)
    - Workbook of designs and patterns; watercolor, undated
  - Humphrey, Laura and Nancy
    - Rewards of merit (4) and keepsakes (3); holograph with watercolor, 1800, undated (Box 23, Folder 427)
    - Samplers, embroidery on linen, 1800, undated (Box 23, Folder 428)
  - Jackson, Andrew
    - Letter to Andrew Jackson Jr., regarding family matters, 1824 Apr 5 (Box 23, Folder 429)
  - Johnson, Lady Bird
    - Letter to William Wise, E. P. Dutton & Company, regarding gift of book, 1966 Jul 22 (Box 23, Folder 430)
  - Key, Francis Scott
    - Letter to Charles Henry Key, regarding his studies, 1840 Jun 20 (Box 23, Folder 431)
  - King, Martin Luther
    - Letters (2) to students at George Washington Elementary School, Compton, California; with photocopy of letter from students to King, 1965, undated (Box 23, Folder 432)
  - Kutting, Phebe P.
    - Manuscript booklet with notes on the rulers of European countries; holograph, circa 1830 (Box 23, Folder 433)
  - Lincoln, Abraham
    - Letter to Fanny Barrow, in the hand of his secretary John Hay, regarding a gift received; accompanied by a photocopy of a letter from Mary Todd Lincoln also thanking Barrow, and a carte-de-visite portrait of Lincoln and his son, 1864 Oct 19, undated (Box 24, Folder 434)
  - Marlborough (Mass.)
    - Petition by selectmen to be excused for not establishing district school due to Indian attacks, signed by Jonathan Johnson, schoolmaster, and Peter Rice on behalf of the selectmen; holograph, circa 1715 (Box 24, Folder 435)
  - Melvill, Allan
    - Workbook, "Master Allan Melvills [sic] Printing Book" for penmanship at West Boston Academy; holograph, 1793 (Box 24, Folder 436)
  - Nazareth Hall
    - Account book for school (1785-1835); holograph; and letter from H. F. Anners to Rev. C. A. Van Bleck, regarding printing for the school, 1785-1839 (Box 24, Folder 437)
    - "Dialogue upon the Brethrens Mission among the N. American Indians spoken by the second class" at the Vernal Examination in Nazareth School, 18 April 1795, copied by Nathaniel Brown; holograph; with program for Boies Penrose visit to Nazareth Hall Military Academy, 1795, 1914 (Box 24, Folder 438)
  - Packard, Ellen
    - Receipt for teaching salary, Errol, New Hampshire, 1867 Jul 6 (Box 24, Folder 439)
  - Peekskill Military Academy
    - Ledger containing minutes of stockholder meetings, reports, and record of stock share transactions of the Peekskill Academy, 1833-1874 (Box 24, Folder 440)
  - Perry, Moses
    - Agreement with Choctaw agent, William Armstrong, for Perry to teach among the Choctaw Indians; holograph, 1835 Nov 1 (Box 24, Folder 441)
  - Phillips, Lydia
    - Workbook for arithmetic; holograph, 1730 (Box 24, Folder 442)
  - Plumer, William
    - Broadside, "The Writing Master's Invitation and Instruction," Center School; holograph, 1802 May 10
  - Prince, John
    - Letter to William H. Sumner, regarding why he cannot educate Sumner's sister, 1804 Apr 10 (Box 24, Folder 443)
  - Rappleyea, Joseph
    - Workbook, "Cyphering book," for arithmetic; holograph, 1812 (Box 24, Folder 444)
  - Ray, Nicholas
    - "Letters to Mr. Richard Ray Junr. of New-York on several subjects by Nicholas Ray of London"; bound volume of sixteen letters from a merchant to his nephew, 1756-1757 (Box 25, Folder 445)
  - Reinwald, Maria
    - Songbook, "Hermodisches Melodien Büchlein Über die Besanke Lieder im Marburger gesang Buch"; holograph, 1792 (Box 25, Folder 446)
  - Roosevelt, Franklin
    - Letter to Henry Parsons, regarding Boy Scouts, 1927 Dec 20 (Box 25, Folder 447)
  - Rosenbach Company
    - Letter to Sherman Haight, regarding children's books issued between 1808-1828, 1933 Oct 10 (Box 25, Folder 448)
  - Rowson, Mrs.
    - Receipt for tuition, materials, and meals for Lucy Champney, Newton, Massachusetts, 1804 Aug 20 (Box 25, Folder 449)
  - St. Mary's Orphan Home
    - Photograph album, Binghamton, New York, circa 1893 (Box 25, Folder 450)
  - Salem, Massachusetts, citizens
    - Request to town selectmen for balance of funds allocated for a school, 1711 May 4 (Box 25, Folder 451)
  - Smith, John Jay